const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",i="insurance",a=200,n=120,o=[{id:39,question:"The payment made when the insured is  not  entitled to claim under a policy is",option:{a:"voluntary excess",b:"ex-gratia",c:"return premium",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:295,question:"Business interruption insurance can also be called",option:{a:"consequential loss",b:"constructive loss",c:"partial  loss",d:"general loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:38,question:"Effective supervision and licensing of insurance firms in Nigeria is the function of",option:{a:"National Insurance Commission",b:"Institute of Loss Adjusters of Nigeria",c:"Chartered Insurance Institute of Nigeria",d:"Nigerian Corporation of Registered Insurance Brokers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:196,question:"The following are the methods of claim settlement except",option:{a:"Cash",b:"Repair",c:"Reinstatement",d:"Repayment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:127,question:"Re-insurance contract is between",option:{a:"Re-insurer and insurer",b:"Re- insurance and insurance",c:"Co-insurer and insurer",d:"Insurance broker and re-insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:131,question:"The prices set by the insurer for the insurance cover is known as",option:{a:"Due",b:"Levy",c:"Premium",d:"Charge"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:37,question:"Which  of the following activities is  not a  function of the  Chartered  Insurance  Institute  of  Nigeria?",option:{a:"Setting a standard for members",b:"Promoting Professional growth",c:"Promoting the interest of insurers",d:"Specifying professional qualification"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:236,question:"Which of the method below can be used to provide indemnity in the event of loss",option:{a:"moral advice",b:"resolution of policy",c:"cash payment",d:"professional encouragement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:349,question:"Which of the following factors limits indemnity?",option:{a:"Cession",b:"Re - insurance",c:"Excess",d:"Co - insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:108,question:"Which of the following is not a function of insurance?",option:{a:"Serves as collateral",b:"Encouraging saving",c:"Provides insecurity",d:"Reduces risks"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:119,question:"Which of the following is not a principle of insurance",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Insurable risk",c:"Subrogation",d:"Insurable interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:36,question:"The professional service required for effective claims administration by insurers would be provided by",option:{a:"loss assessors",b:"risk managers",c:"loss adjusters",d:"claims consultants"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:139,question:"Consequential loss is also known as",option:{a:"Business interruption insurance",b:"Credit insurance",c:"Excess loss",d:"Property insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:294,question:"A risk that has its origin in the activities of an individual and the effects borne by this individual is called",option:{a:"pure risk",b:"particular risk",c:"speculative risk",d:"fundamental risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:154,question:"---------- is the evidence cover of the risk given to the insured by the insurer",option:{a:"Cover",b:"Policy",c:"Claim",d:"Compensation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:190,question:"When an   insurer agrees   to   replace   irreparably damaged or stolen goods with similar type it is called",option:{a:"Reinstatement",b:"Cash",c:"Repairs",d:"Replacement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:207,question:"The legal right that a person must have to enable him or her to insure his or her property is known as",option:{a:"freedom",b:"franchise",c:"insurable interest",d:"Access right"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:35,question:"Risk Net Insurance Brokers Limited placed a business with an insurance company, in return the broker will be entitled to",option:{a:"fees",b:"commission",c:"profit",d:"revenue"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:109,question:"In the utmost good faith principle, the value of the subject matter should",option:{a:"Be over stated",b:"Understated",c:"Not be stated",d:"Not be overstated nor understated"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:66,question:"Insured is likewise known as",option:{a:"insuree",b:"Insurer",c:"policy holder",d:"contractor"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:113,question:"A peril is best defined as",option:{a:"Chance of a loss",b:"The occurrence of a loan",c:"The cause of a loss",d:"The result of a loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:331,question:"A motorist travelling from Ghana to Nigeria would be required to obtain one of the following types of motor insurance cover",option:{a:"green card",b:"brown card",c:"yellow card",d:"purple card"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:280,question:"An  attempt  to  deprive  someone of his  property is",option:{a:"theft",b:"burglary",c:"robbery",d:"larceny"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:262,question:"One of this is a method of claim settlement",option:{a:"price",b:"trade by barter",c:"exchange",d:"cash"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:245,question:"A reminder to the insured that this existing contract is due to expire is",option:{a:"proposal form",b:"slip",c:"claim form",d:"renewal notice"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:242,question:"A written amendment in addition or alterations to the information stated in the policy is called",option:{a:"endorsement",b:"specification",c:"construction",d:"attestation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:198,question:"A payment made by insurer as a form of sympathy to maintain goodwill is",option:{a:"Compensation payment",b:"Contract payment",c:"Charity payment",d:"Ex - gratia payment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:317,question:"A clause in an insurance policy that makes a claim jointly payable to the policyholder and the third party is",option:{a:"claim clause",b:"mortgagee clause",c:"mortgage clause",d:"joint liability clause"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:95,question:"The person  that  brings  an insurance  contract  into existence between  the principal and third party  is a/an",option:{a:"agent",b:"bailee",c:"contractor",d:"insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:151,question:"--------- shows what the insured should do or not do to maintain the existence of the policy",option:{a:"Cover note",b:"Policy",c:"Warranty",d:"Certificate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:284,question:"Return premium is the same thing as",option:{a:"premium payment",b:"premium refund",c:"premium tax",d:"premium bonus"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:159,question:"The price of insurance is known as",option:{a:"Rate",b:"Interest",c:"Premium",d:"Profit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:171,question:"The shifting of responsibility of one’s own losses to another is known as ---------- transfer",option:{a:"Fund",b:"Risk",c:"Business",d:"Policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:123,question:"Risk whose cause is beyond human control is",option:{a:"Fundamental",b:"Speculative",c:"Particular",d:"Static"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:22,question:"One of the information contained in a motor insurance cover note is the",option:{a:"behaviour of the insured",b:"occupation of the insured",c:"commencement date",d:"previous and present insurance history"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:195,question:"Application by the insured to the insurer for the payment of money due under his contract of insurance is",option:{a:"Proof",b:"Evidence",c:"Claim",d:"Compensation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:337,question:"The  document issued by  the  insurer when there is a change in the particulars of a risk insured is",option:{a:"endorsement",b:"certificate",c:"voucher",d:"policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:334,question:"The process of  assessing  risks  in  insurance  and classifying them according to their degree of insurability so  that  the  appropriate  rate  may  be  assigned  is",option:{a:"inspecting",b:"underwriting",c:"surveying",d:"evaluating"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:105,question:"Which of the following is not a principle of insurance?",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Compensation",c:"Proximate cause",d:"Insurable interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:240,question:"One of these shows the introduction to the details of the insurance policy, parties as well as the premium for the contract",option:{a:"preamble",b:"heading",c:"exception",d:"condition"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:350,question:"A  temporary  insurance  document  providing  coverage until a permanent policy is issued is",option:{a:"proposal form",b:"cover note",c:"policy document",d:"insurance certificate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:7,question:"In  classification  of  risks, what is the name given to a risk  where  the  causes  of  events are linked to factors 	that are due to the society we live in?",option:{a:"Dynamic risk",b:"Particular risk",c:"Speculative risk",d:"Fundamental risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:52,question:"An  insurance  feature  that  requires  the  parties  to disclose  all  material  facts  about  the  agreement is known as",option:{a:"Adhesion",b:"Disclosure",c:"Material fact",d:"Utmost good faith"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:329,question:"The  sum  insured  for  a  risk  is  N= 150,000  and  was accepted  for  fire  insurance at a rate of  0.25%. How much will the insured pay as a premium?",option:{a:"N= 125",b:"N= 375",c:"N= 500",d:"N= 875"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:110,question:"Which of the following is non- insurable risk?",option:{a:"Gambling",b:"Accident",c:"Fire",d:"Theft"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:75,question:"The following risks are insurable except",option:{a:"particular",b:"pure",c:"static",d:"dynamic risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:327,question:"Which of the following is not a function of an insurance underwriter?",option:{a:"Determining rates and coverage for the risk",b:"Deciding whether to take the risk",c:"Looking for an insurer to take the risk",d:"Deciding whether to reject the risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:51,question:"The primary function of insurance is",option:{a:"making profit",b:"managing of risk",c:"spreading of risk",d:"prevention of accident"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:299,question:"The party who proposes to the insurance company to insure his properly is called",option:{a:"offeree",b:"offeror",c:"acceptance party",d:"offer client"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:308,question:"A type of re - insurance  where  the re - insurer has  the option  to  accept  or  reject  any  risk  presented  for re-insurance is",option:{a:"stop loss",b:"facultative",c:"treaty",d:"excess of loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:258,question:"One of the following is necessary to meet uncertainties in future",option:{a:"profit",b:"capital",c:"borrowing",d:"insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:291,question:"The full meaning of NAICOM is",option:{a:"Nigerian insurance company",b:"national insurance commission",c:"national insurer commission",d:"national insured commission"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:179,question:"The policy that covers loss of cash while in transit or at home is --------------- insurance",option:{a:"Burglary",b:"Business interruption",c:"Credit",d:"Money"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:251,question:"Insurance premium depends on the",option:{a:"amount of profit to be made by the insurer",b:"various insurance companies in a place",c:"extent of the possible loss and the frequency of risk",d:"supply and demand"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:269,question:"To which of the following does the principle of utmost good faith apply in a contract of insurance?",option:{a:"the insurer only",b:"the proposer only",c:"the third party and insured",d:"insurer and proposer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:222,question:"A contract that is contrary to public policy is",option:{a:"valid contract",b:"legal contract",c:"illegal contract",d:"voidable contract"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:343,question:"Which of the following activities is not involved in claims management?",option:{a:"Proof of loss",b:"Particulars of loss",c:"Premium calculation",d:"Primary investigation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:45,question:"The consideration paid for insurance contract is",option:{a:"money",b:"commission",c:"premium",d:"fee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:225,question:"The process of evaluating and minimizing risk is",option:{a:"risk management",b:"risk certainty",c:"risk insurance",d:"risk re-grouping"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:216,question:"With assurance contract there is",option:{a:"uncertainly of reward",b:"certainty of reward",c:"certainty of occurrence",d:"uncertainty of occurrence"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:99,question:"A policy designed to protect individuals against negligence while carrying out their daily activities is called",option:{a:"business interruption",b:"employers liability",c:"engineering",d:"professional indemnity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:90,question:"Any circumstance that promotes the probability of a loss is called",option:{a:"accident",b:"hazard",c:"loss",d:"risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:275,question:"A contract which has no legal effect is called",option:{a:"void policy",b:"voidable policy",c:"legal policy",d:"formal policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:223,question:"Which of the following cannot enter into an insurance contract?",option:{a:"adult",b:"insured",c:"minor",d:"insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:44,question:"Insurers A and B cover a risk at the ratio of 2:5 for the sum insured of N= 1,800. How much would insurer  A get from the risk?",option:{a:"N= 1,285.00",b:"N= 771.00",c:"N= 514.00",d:"N= 180.00"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:335,question:"Who  among  the  following  is  an  employer  of  loss adjuster?",option:{a:"Insurer",b:"Broker",c:"Insured",d:"Agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:323,question:"A clause in marine insurance policy prohibiting the insured from giving up a damaged property is",option:{a:"deductible",b:"abandonment",c:"indemnity",d:"compensation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:50,question:"Which of the following is not a function of an insurance broker?",option:{a:"Assisting clients in paying premium",b:"Maintaining proper records of claims",c:"Assisting clients in connecting to insurers",d:"Assisting clients in effecting uninsured loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:29,question:"A provision in a policy that exempts an insurer from liability if the loss is less than a certain amount is",option:{a:"excess",b:"transfer",c:"lay days",d:"franchise"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:261,question:"The settlement of disagreement between the insured and the insurer is called",option:{a:"litigation",b:"arbitration",c:"negotiation",d:"compromising"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:141,question:"The acronym “CllN” refers to",option:{a:"Certified insurance institute",b:"Certified insured institute",c:"Certified international institute",d:"Chartered insurance institute"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:234,question:"The following classes of insurance apply the use of proposal form except",option:{a:"public liability",b:"large risk of marine insurance",c:"small risk of marine insurance",d:"theft"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:200,question:"Another name for an insured in a life insurance contract is",option:{a:"Insurer",b:"Assured",c:"Assurer",d:"Agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:93,question:"Subrogation principle can be applied in the following insurance policies except in",option:{a:"aviation policy",b:"engineering policy",c:"life policy",d:"marine policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:321,question:"A policy taken for full protection against fire and other risks such as flood, tempest, riot and civil commotion is",option:{a:"consequential loss",b:"fire and all risks policy",c:"combined householder’s policy",d:"fire and special perils"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:53,question:"An insurance principle that requires the insured to be honest and disclose all relevant facts is called",option:{a:"subrogation",b:"utmost good faith",c:"proximate cause",d:"insurable interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:182,question:"A professional officer of an insurance company whose duty among others is to calculate the premium to be 	paid by the insured is called",option:{a:"Agent",b:"Principal",c:"Actuarist",d:"Adjuster"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:118,question:"The principle of subrogation imposed an obligation on the insured to",option:{a:"Disclose all material information",b:"Have financial risks in the object",c:"Press for compensation",d:"Surrender legal right after compensation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:268,question:"The payment made when the insured is not entitled to claim under a policy is",option:{a:"voluntary excess",b:"ex-gratia",c:"return premium",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:318,question:"The policy that covers  an  insured  employee  against injury  sustained  in  the  course  of  employment  is",option:{a:"professional indemnity",b:"product liability",c:"public liability",d:"employer’s liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:163,question:"A  Statement signed by the insured, certifying the Statement",option:{a:"Certificate",b:"Declaration",c:"Confirmation slip",d:"Accuracy statement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:104,question:"The term pooling of risks in insurance means that",option:{a:"Many who face risks pay premium so that those who suffer loss may be reimbursed",b:"Insurance companies share heavy losses",c:"Insurance company re-assures with another",d:"Insurance companies operates pool betting business"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:281,question:"The process of examining, accepting or rejecting risks and classifying the ones accepted is",option:{a:"underwriting",b:"policy",c:"procedures",d:"warranty"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:217,question:"Indemnity is not applicable in",option:{a:"assurance contract",b:"insurance contract",c:"insurance terms",d:"insurance content"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:211,question:"An insurance contract where both parties signed the agreement which involve mutuality of agreement is known as",option:{a:"unilateral contract",b:"multilateral contract",c:"bilateral contract",d:"united contract"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:315,question:"Which  of  the  following  would  not  give  cause  for subrogation right?",option:{a:"Benefit",b:"Contract",c:"Statute",d:"Salvage"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:246,question:"One of these is a form of motor vehicle insurance policy",option:{a:"comprehensive",b:"1st party only",c:"2nd party only",d:"accident"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:133,question:"When an insured person admits that he has indemnified, he means that",option:{a:"The damage proper by has been recovered",b:"He was paid premium fully",c:"The insurance company has restored him to his former position",d:"He was paid his premium fully"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:3,question:"An assurance policy taken by experts to cover possible negligence arising from their duties is",option:{a:"consequential loss",b:"professional indemnity",c:"cargo",d:"freight"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:221,question:"A contract which has no legal effect is called",option:{a:"voidable contract",b:"legal contract",c:"void contract",d:"valid contract"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:68,question:"The buyer of insurance product is",option:{a:"Agent",b:"Broker",c:"Insured",d:"Insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:158,question:"The cause of a loss is known as",option:{a:"Peril",b:"Hazard",c:"Loss",d:"Risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:185,question:"In insurance contract, failure to disclose all relevant material facts will render the contract",option:{a:"legal",b:"Voidable",c:"Void",d:"Implied"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:311,question:"Which  of  the  following  statements  is  true  about property insurance?",option:{a:"The probability that the event may occur",b:"The probability that the event will not occur",c:"The probability that the event may or may not occur",d:"The probability that the event must occur"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:69,question:"The seller of insurance product is",option:{a:"Insurer",b:"Insured",c:"Broker",d:"Agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:270,question:"A method of providing indemnity in the event of loss is",option:{a:"cash payment",b:"professional advice",c:"resolution of policy",d:"resolution of dispute"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:201,question:"Insurance is defined as",option:{a:"risking of loss",b:"pooling of risk",c:"gathering of risk",d:"waiving of risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:55,question:"A  statement  of  fact  that  the insured must have an interest in the object of the contract is called",option:{a:"warranty",b:"insurable interest",c:"subrogation",d:"object interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:290,question:"Marine insurance policy which covers all the ship or vessels belonging to one owner is",option:{a:"flect policy",b:"mixed policy",c:"value policy",d:"fixed policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:203,question:"The premium paid by the insured to the insurance company is",option:{a:"capital",b:"commission",c:"common fund",d:"consideration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:152,question:"The uncertainty of an event occurring is known as",option:{a:"Hazard",b:"Risk",c:"Loss",d:"Accident"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:209,question:"In insurance, uncertainty of loss means",option:{a:"hazard",b:"risk",c:"accident",d:"earthquake"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:168,question:"A place where the business of insurance is transacted is called a/an",option:{a:"Insurance market",b:"Brokerage firm",c:"Insurance house",d:"Insurance conference room"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:84,question:"A person who has lawful possession of goods belonging to another is known as",option:{a:"Owner",b:"Bailee",c:"Agent",d:"Trustee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:232,question:"When the proposer fails to fill the proposal form truthfully, the contract will become",option:{a:"voidable",b:"illegal",c:"void",d:"enforceable"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:172,question:"A financial compensation sufficient to return the insured back to his original position after loss is known as",option:{a:"Deposit",b:"Loan",c:"Indemnity",d:"Overdraft"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:174,question:"A marine policy that provider cover for the construction of sea vessels is called --------- policy",option:{a:"Building",b:"Mixed",c:"Port",d:"Valued"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:175,question:"Spreading of risk to ensure that no insurer is liquidated by the occurrence of a large loss is the concept of",option:{a:"Insurance",b:"Re insurance",c:"Renewal",d:"Treaty"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:288,question:"Marine  losses are divided into",option:{a:"actual total and total loss",b:"total loss and partial loss",c:"partial loss and actual loss",d:"average loss and partial loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:67,question:"Insurance contract is between",option:{a:"Broker and Agent",b:"Insured and Insurer",c:"Insurer  and Agent",d:"Insured and Agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:208,question:"An undertaking by the insured that certain things shall be done or not be done or certain things shall be put in place or not in place is called",option:{a:"warranties and representation",b:"utmost good faith and uberrimae fidei",c:"insurable and non-insurable",d:"subrogation and indemnity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:313,question:"Which class of life assurance would a young couple who desires to start a new business in five years time purchase?",option:{a:"Whole life policy",b:"Limited whole life policy",c:"Keyman policy",d:"Endowment policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:13,question:"The class of non-life insurance policy where cover note is issued is",option:{a:"fire insurance",b:"burglary insurance",c:"motor insurance",d:"fidelity guarantee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:283,question:"The amount added to the standard premium in respect of the larger than standard risk presented by the proposer is called",option:{a:"premium increase",b:"premium loading",c:"premium payment",d:"premium commission"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:220,question:"A buyer of insurance product is",option:{a:"insured",b:"promise",c:"insurer",d:"insuree"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:46,question:"The alternative to seeking for surrender value in a life assurance contract is",option:{a:"automatic non - forfeiture",b:"revival condition",c:"paid-up policy",d:"standing order"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:339,question:"Which of the following documents forms the basis of a contract in insurance business?",option:{a:"Policy document",b:"Proposal form",c:"Claim form",d:"Discharge form"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:165,question:"Life assurance provides dual benefits of savings and ------------ to a policy holder",option:{a:"Acceptance",b:"Consideration",c:"Contribution",d:"Security"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:32,question:"A contract sold  by  insurance companies that  pay  a monthly or  quarterly income  benefit for the  life  of a person is",option:{a:"endowment",b:"annuity",c:"income",d:"freight"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:274,question:"A reinsurance contract in which the reassured agrees to offer and the reinsurer agrees to accept all risks of certain size within a defined class is",option:{a:"underwriting",b:"treaty",c:"tort",d:"syndicate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"}],t={message:e,subject:i,status:200,total:120,data:o};export{o as data,t as default,e as message,a as status,i as subject,n as total};
